Guide to the James Joyce Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE, 1900-1952; (5 boxes)
  - LETTERS ABOUT THE PUBLICATION OF JOYCE'S WORKS
    - 1915-1929 (Box 2, Folder 69)
      1928 Apr 5 Tomlinson, Paul G. TL to James R. Wells
      carbon copy
      1928 Jun 7 Tomlinson, Paul G. TL to Frederic Warde
      1928 Jul 10 Unidentified Telegram to unidentified
      1928 Jul 12 Warde, Frederic Telegram to Paul G.
      Tomlinson
      1928 Jul 12 Tomlinson, Paul G. TL to Frederic Warde
      1928 Jul 19 Tomlinson, Paul G. TL to Frederic Warde
      1928 Jul 25 Tomlinson, Paul G. TL to Frederic Warde
      1928 Jul 25 Warde, Frederic ALS to Paul G. Tomlinson
      1928 Aug 17 Tomlinson, Paul G. TL to Frederic Warde
      1929 Apr 18 Warde, Frederic TLS to Paul G. Tomlinson
      1929 Apr 19 Tomlinson, Paul G. TL to Frederic Warde
      1929 Apr 22 Warde, Frederic TLS to Paul G. Tomlinson
      1929 Apr 24 Tomlinson, Paul G. TL to Frederic Warde
      1929 Apr 30 Warde, Frederic TL to Paul G. Tomlinson
    - 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 70)
      1930 Feb 6 Kahane, Jack TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1930 Aug 5 James B. Pinker & Sons
      Receipt for royalties
      1930 Sep 12 Pinker, Eric TL to Ralph Pinker
      1930 Sep 22 Harrap, George G. TLS to James Pinker &
      Sons
      1930 Sep 25 Harrap, George G. TLS to James B. Pinker
      & Sons
      1931 Jun 18 Pollinger, Laurence Edward TLS to Ralph
      Pinker Accompanied by a photocopy of the injunction
      (37 (sic) Dec 1928) against Samuel Roth. photocopy
      [from unknown source]
      1931 Jul 4 Beach, Sylvia TLS to James B. Pinker & Son
      1931 Dec 16 Conner, Benjamin Howe TL to James Joyce
    - 1932 (Box 2, Folder 71)
      1932 Jan 14 Alfred Imhoff, Ltd.
      Receipt on Joyce's account
      1932 Jul 14 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1932 Aug 3 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1932 Aug 6 Rubin, N. H. TLS to James Joyce
      No date Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      after 1932 Aug 8
      1932 Aug 18 Harmsworth, Desmond TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1932 Sep 8 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1932 Sep 27 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1932 Oct 26 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      photocopy [from unknown source ]
      1932 Oct 28 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1932 Oct 31 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1932 Nov 7 Verhulst, Carolus TL to James Joyce
      typed copy
      1932 Nov 9 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1932 Nov 9 Morley, F. V. TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1932 Nov 9 Morley, F. V. TL to James Joyce
      1932 Nov ? Morley, F. V.
      Memorandum
      1932 Nov 11 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1932 Nov 15 Verhulst, Carolus TLS to Paul Léon
      1932 Nov 17 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1932 Nov 17 Léon, Paul TL to F. V. Morley
      1932 Nov 18 Morley, F. V. TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1932 Nov 18 Morley, F. V. TL to B. W. Huebsch
      1932 Nov 19 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1932 Nov 22 Morley, F. V. TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1932 Nov 22 Morley, F. V. TL to Paul Léon
      1932 Nov 23 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1932 Nov 23 Léon, Paul TL to F. V. Morley
      1932 Nov 28 Léon, Paul TLS to Alfred Bergan
      1932 Dec 1 Léon, Paul TL to Ralph Pinker
      1932 Dec 9 Morley, F. V. TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1932 Dec 9 Morley, F. V. TL to Paul Léon
      1932 Dec 14 Pinker, Eric TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1932 Dec 27 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
    - 1933 (Box 2, Folder 72)
      1933 Jan 3 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Jan 10 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Jan 18 Brooks, C. H. TLS to James Joyce
      1933 Jan 23 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Jan 23 Léon, Paul TLS to F. V. Morley
      1933 Jan 26 Brooks, C. H. TLS to James B. Pinker &
      Son
      1933 Jan 27 Morley, F. V. TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Jan 28 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Feb 18 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Feb 19 Léon, Paul TLS to Alfred Bergan
      1933 Feb 19 Risolo, Amania ALS to Paul Léon
      1933 Feb 22 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Feb 25 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Mar 6 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Mar 14 Léon, Paul TLS to Alfred Bergan
      1933 Mar 14 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Mar 16 Morley, F. V. TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Mar 16 Morley, F. V. TL to Paul Léon
      1933 Mar 20 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Mar 27 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Apr 3 Léon, Paul TL to Ralph Pinker
      1933 May 1 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 May 12 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 May 18 Verhulst, Carolus TLS to James B. Pinker
      & Son
      1933 May 26 Huebsch, B. W. TL to Eric Pinker
      1933 Jul 24 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Aug 9 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Aug 17 Léon, Paul ALS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Aug 18 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Oct 23 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Oct 27 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Oct 31 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Dec 4 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Dec 8 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1933 Dec 9 R J TLS to James B. Pinker
      1933 Dec 27 Butterworth, Thornton TLS to Louis
      Golding
    - 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 73)
      1934 Jan 3 Léon, Paul TL to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Jan 4 Wegner, M. C. TL to Paul Léon
      1934 Jan 5 Léon, Paul TL to M. C. Wegner
      1934 Jan 6 Léon, Paul TLS to M. C. Wegner
      1934 Jan 6 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Jan 6 Léon, Paul Telegram to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Jan 14 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Jan 18 Lane, Allen TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Jan 23 Lane, Allen TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Jan 28 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Jan 29 Agenzia Letteraria Internazionale
      TL to James B. Pinker & Son
      1934 Jan 30 Monro, Saw & Co. TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Feb 14 Léon, Paul ALS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Mar 2 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Mar 14 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 May 4 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 May 10 Watson, Frances
      Receipt on account with James B. Pinker & Son
      1934 May 10 Morley, F. V. TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 May 14 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Jul 2 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Jul 17 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Jul 21 Lane, Allen TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Jul 25 Léon, Paul ALS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Aug 8 New York Herald Press Press Release
      1934 Aug 9 Lane, Allen TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Aug 11 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Aug 14 Monro, Saw & Co. TLS to James B. Pinker
      1934 Aug 16 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Aug 21 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Aug 26 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Aug 29 Lane, Allen TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Sep 17 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Sep ? James B. Pinker & Son TL to Paul Léon
      1934 Sep 25 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Oct 1 Lane, Allen TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Oct 10 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Nov 1 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Nov 15 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Nov 21 Lane, Allen TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Nov 22 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Nov 27 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Nov 29 Morley, F. V. TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Dec 4 Lane, Allen TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Dec 14 Lane, Allen TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1934 Dec 29 Léon, Paul TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1935 Jun 7 Beach, Sylvia TLS to Elkin Mathews, Ltd.
- SERIES II. WRITINGS, 1903-1955; (14 boxes)
  - WORKS BY JOYCE
    - AD WRITER Typescript 1p., 1932
      E 13 b See: SERIES I, Box 1, folder 13
    - AESTHETICS Manuscript 3p., 1903 (Box 3, Folder 74)
      E 17 d
    - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE
      See: FINNEGANS WAKE, Box 5, folder 100
    - LA BATTAGLIA FRA BERNARD SHAW E LA CENSURA Typescript 2p., [1909] (Box 3, Folder 75)
      Typed copy and carbon in Italian, and a
      typescript of the translation into
      English with G. R. Shaw's autograph
      notes; accompanied by two carbon copies
      of the English translation.
    - THE BOARDING HOUSE
      See: DUBLINERS, Box 4, folder 88
    - CHAMBER MUSIC Manuscript 37p., 1905 (Box 3, Folder 76)
      E 1 b
    - CHAMBER MUSIC Manuscript 37p., 1906 (Box 3, Folder 77)
      E 1 c
    - CHAMBER MUSIC: XI Manuscript 1p., 1904 (Box 3, Folder 78)
      Accompanied by a letter of
      authentication.
    - CHAMBER MUSIC: XX Manuscript lp., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - CHAMBER MUSIC: XXV Manuscript 1p., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - CHAMBER MUSIC: XXXV Manuscript lp., 1902
      E 1 e ii See: ALS from James Joyce to
      John F. Byrne,-dated 1902 Dec 15 in
      SERIES I, Box 1, folder 5
    - CHRISTMAS EVE Manuscript 3p., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 81)
      Page 3 of this ms is at Cornell
      accompanied by a photocopy of the
      complete manuscript.
    - LA COMETA DELL' "HOME RULE" Manuscript, n.d.; 12 pages (Box 3, Folder 82)
      E 9
    - A CURIOUS HISTORY Typescript 2p., 1911 (Box 3, Folder 83)
      E 11 b viii The typescript is a copy
      of the article as it appeared in Sinn
      Fein. Accompanied by a printed version
      from The Northern Whig (1911)
    - A CURIOUS HISTORY Typescript 4p., 1913 (Box 3, Folder 84)
      E 11 b viii Typed copy of the article
      as it appeared in The Egoist
    - THE DAY OF THE RABBLEMENT Proof copy, 1910 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - p. [7]-8
      Corrected and signed by Joyce.
    - THE DEAD
      See: DUBLINERS, Box 4, folder 95
    - DOOLEYSPRUDENCE
      See: MR. DOOLEY, Box 6, folder 134
    - DUBLINERS
      Manuscripts of all of the stories except Araby, Eveline, After the Race, Two Gallants, A Little Cloud, and Clay are in the Beinecke Library. The Manuscripts are too fragile to be used except under very special circumstances. photocopies have been provided for general use.
      - THE SISTERS Manuscript 10p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 86)
        E 2 a
      - AN ENCOUNTER Manuscript 16p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 87)
        E 2 b
      - THE BOARDING HOUSE Manuscript 17p., 1905 (Box 4, Folder 88)
        E 2 C
      - COUNTERPARTS Manuscript 24p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 89)
        E 2 d Last leaf missing
      - A PAINFUL CASE Manuscript 20p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 90)
        E 2 e i Last leaf missing
      - A PAINFUL CASE Manuscript 24p., 1905 (Box 4, Folder 91)
        E 2 e ii
      - IVY DAY IN THE COMMITTEE ROOM, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 92)
      - Manuscript 23p.
        E 2 f
      - A MOTHER Manuscript 18p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 93)
        E 2 g
      - GRACE Manuscript 36p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 94)
        E 2 h
      - THE DEAD Manuscript 25p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 95)
        E 2 i Title page, p. 1-19, 57,
        74-77 only
      - Corrections to DUBLINERS Manuscript, [1915] (Box 4, Folder 96)
      - lp. E 2 j
      - DUBLINERS Page proofs, 1910
        In: Beinecke Library Iq.J853.D76.1910
      - DUBLINERS Galley proofs, 1910
        In: Beinecke Library Iq.J853.D76.1910A
      - DUBLINERS Page proofs, 1914
        In: Beinecke Library Iq.J853.D76.1914A
    - AN ENCOUNTER
      See: DUBLINERS, Box 4, folder 87
    - EPILOGUE TO IBSEN'S "GHOSTS" Typescript, n.d.
    - 2p.
      See: SERIES I, Box 1, Folder 6
    - EXILES Manuscript 169p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 97-97b)
      E 4 b
    - EXILES shipping envelope, 1917 Jun 6 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - EXILES exhibition notes, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Corrections to EXILES Manuscript, 1918
      - E 4 c
        See: ALS from James Joyce to Grant Richards, dated 1918 Jun 6 in SERIES I, Box 1, folder 21
    - FATHER O'FLYNN: parody Typescript 1p., 1931
      E 17 b ix See: TL from James Joyce to
      Harriet Weaver, dated 1931 Feb 16 in
      SERIES I. Box 1, folder 27
    - FINNEGANS WAKE: The manuscript material in Box 5 was purchased in 1967 from Maurice Saillet with monies from the Beinecke Rare Book Endowment Fund. A complete listing of manuscript and printed material received by this purchase is laid in the front of the box.
    - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE Page proofs 14p., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 100)
      Proofs, heavily corrected by Joyce, for
      the first publication of Anna Livia in
      La Navire, 1 Oct 1925.
    - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE Page proofs 15p., 1925 (Box 5, Folder 101)
      Second proofs, corrected by Joyce, of
      the above.
    - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE: French, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Translation Typescript 2p.
      Typescript of the first French
      translation by Samuel Beckett and
      Alfred Peron. Accompanied by a letter
      from Beckett to Phillipe Soupault,
      dated 1930 Jul 5.
    - [EMPTY FOLDER] (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE: French, [1930]
    - Translation Galley proofs 7p.
      Proofs of the above, with corrections
      in pen by Beckett and in pencil by
      Peron.
    - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE: French, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Translation Typescript 10p.
      Typescript of the second French
      translation by Beckett and Peron.
    - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE French, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Translation Typescript 7p.
      Same as the above. Accompanied by a
      note in Joyce's hand and with his
      corrections.
    - Monnier, Adrienne TL to Gaston Gallimard 2p., 1931 Jun 18 (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Monnier, Adrienne AL to Germaine Pascal 1p., 1931 Jun 20 (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - FINNEGANS WAKE: The following 7 folders are part of the Collection of James Joyce formed by John J. Slocum. (Re: the Crosby Gaige edition, 1928)
    - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE Galley proof (A) 13l., 1928 (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE Galley proof (B) 16l., [1928] (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE Galley proof (C) 13l., [1928] (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE Galley proof (D) 17l., 1928 (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE: Introduction, [1928] (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - Typescript 5p.
      Setting typescript of the introduction
      by Padraic Colum.
    - Beach, Sylvia TLS to Crosby Gaige lp., 1928 Jun 7 (Box 5, Folder 113)
      Contains corrections to ANNA LIVIA.
    - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE Final page proofs 19p., 1928 (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - FINNEGANS WAKE: The following 4 folders are part of the Collection of James Joyce formed by John J. Slocum. (Re: the Crosby Gaige edition, 1928)
    - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE, [1928] (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - Layouts 28p.
      Layouts in three sections: (1) the
      preface; (2) the text; and (3) the
      signature to be sent to Europe for
      Joyce to sign.
    - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE Page proofs 25p., [1928] (Box 5, Folder 116)
      Three sets of page proofs of the first
      signature (title page) and one proof of
      the initial "O".
    - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE Layout 42l, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 117)
      Final layout
    - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE Printing invoice and envelope for proofs (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - Correspondence about this edition of ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE may be found in SERIES I.
    - FINNEGANS WAKE: The following 11 folders are the gift of John Hay Whitney, 1965. They consists of three fragments from Work in Progress, Paris, The Black Sun Press, 1929, from the setting typescripts through the third proofs.
    - THE MOOKSE AND THE GRIPES Setting typescript: p. 5-16 (Box 5, Folder 119)
      With Joyce's corrections.
    - THE MOOKSE AND THE GRIPES First proofs: p. 1-13. (Box 5, Folder 120)
      Complete; with Joyce's corrections.
    - THE MOOKSE AND THE GRIPES Second proofs: p. 1-13. (Box 5, Folder 121)
      Complete; with Joyce's corrections and
      a page added in his hand.
    - THE MUDDEST THICK THAT WAS EVER HEARD DUMP Setting typescript: p. 8, 8b, 11, 11b, 14-26 (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - THE MUDDEST THICK THAT WAS EVER HEARD DUMP Second proofs: p. 25-48. (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - THE ONDT AND THE GRACEHOPER Setting typescript: p. 1-12. (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - THE ONDT AND THE GRACEHOPER First proof: 1l. (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - THE ONDT AND THE GRACEHOPER Fourth proof: p. 52-55 (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - THE ONDT AND THE GRACEHOPER First proofs: p. 14-21 (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - Beach, Sylvia 3 ALS Paris, to Harry Crosby, 1928 Oct 12 (Box 5, Folder 128)
    - Paris, to Harry Crosby, 1929 Mar 19
    - Paris, to Caresse Crosby, 1929 Mar 23
    - Beckley, Pendleton TLS to James Joyce Paris, 1929 Mar 27 (Box 5, Folder 129)
    - FOR HE'S A JOLLY GOOD FELLOW: Parody, 1927
    - Typescript 1p.
      E 17 b vi See: TL from James Joyce to
      Harriet Weaver, dated 1927 Feb 1 in
      SERIES I, Box 2, Folder 27.
    - GIACOMO CLARENZIO MANGAN Manuscript, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - 24p.
      E 17 a. Lacks p. 5, 11 and 23.
    - GRACE
      See: DUBLINERS, Box 4, folder 94
    - THE HOLY OFFICE Manuscript 2p., n.d. (Box 6, Folder 131)
      E 11 a vii
    - HUMPTY DUMPTY: Parody Manuscript lp., 1939
      E 17 b x See: ALS from James Joyce to
      Frank Budgen, dated 1939 Sep 5, in
      SERIES I, Box 1, Folder 4.
    - L'IRLANDE ISOLA DEI SANTI E DEI SANI (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - Manuscript 46p.
      E 11 b xii
    - IVY DAY IN THE COMMITTEE ROOM
      See: DUBLINERS, Box 4, folder 92
    - JOHN EGLINGTON, MY JO, JOHN Typescript, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - 1p.
      Two carbon copies.
    - MR. DOOLEY Typescript 2p., n.d. (Box 6, Folder 134)
      E 11 b xvi
    - THE MOOKSE AND THE GRIPES
      See: FINNEGANS WAKE, Box 5, folder 119
    - A MOTHER
      See: DUBLINERS, Box 4, folder 93
    - THE MUDDEST THICK THAT WAS EVER HEARD DUMP
      See: FINNEGANS WAKE, Box 5, folder 122
    - O, THERE ARE TWO BROTHERS, THE FAYS, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Manuscript lp.
      E 17 b i
    - THE ONDT AND THE GRACEHOPER
      See: FINNEGANS WAKE, Box 5, folder 124
    - OSCAR WILDE: IL POETA DI SALOME, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 136)
    - Typescript 4p.
      E 8 English translation Accompanied
      by a TLS from Herbert Cahoon to
      Marjorie Wynne, dated 1959 Feb 5.
    - POMES PENYEACH: A MEMORY OF THE PLAYERS IN A MIRROR (Box 6, Folder 137)
      - Typescript 1 p., n.d.
      - Copy
    - A PORTRAIT OF THE ARTIST AS A YOUNG MAN: Corrections (Box 6, Folder 138)
      - Manuscript 7 p., 1916
      - E 3 d
    - A PORTRAIT OF THE ARTIST AS A YOUNG MAN: The Egoist, tearsheets corrected by James Joyce and Harriet Weaver 1911-15 [with letter from Harriet Weaver to B.W. Huebsch 1916 Sep 7] (Box 6, Folder 139)
    - A PORTRAIT OF THE ARTIST AS A YOUNG MAN: The Egoist, printed pages corrected by James Joyce and Harriet Weaver, 1914-15 (Box 6, Folder 139a-b)
    - A PORTRAIT OF THE ARTIST AS A YOUNG MAN: STEPHEN HERO (Box 6, Folder 140)
      - Manuscript 25 l., n.d.
      - E 3 b ii
    - A PORTRAIT OF THE ARTIST AS A YOUNG MAN: STEPHEN HERO (Box 6, Folder 141)
      - Illustrations 9 l., n.d.
      - By Ducass; Removed from James Joyce, Stephen le Héros, Gallimard, 1948.
    - Quinet, Edgar (Box 6, Folder 142)
      - Quotation used on p. 281 of Finnegans Wake: Manuscript 2 p., n.d.
      - E 13 a Copy in Joyce's hand; photocopy.
    - REVIEWS AND ARTICLES
      - "George Meredith", review of George Meredith: An Essay Towards Appreciation by Walter Jerrold, printed version, Daily Express, Dublin, 1903 Dec 11 (Box 6, Folder 142a)
        C 3
      - "An Irish Poet", review of Poems and Ballads of William Rooney, printed version Daily Express, Dublin, 1903 Dec 11 (Box 6, Folder 142b)
        C 4
      - "To-day and To-morrow in Ireland", review of To-day and To-morrow in Ireland by Stephen Gwynn, printed version, Daily Express, Dublin, 1903 Jan 29 (Box 6, Folder 142c)
        C 5
      - "A Suave Philosophy", review of The Soul of a People by H. Fielding Hall, printed version, Daily Express, Dublin, 1903 Feb 6 (Box 6, Folder 142)
        C 6
      - "An Effort at Precision in Thinking", review of Colloquies of Common People reported by James Austie [i.e. Anstie], K.C.; and "Colonial Verses", review of Songs of an English Esau by Clive Phillipps Wolley, printed versions, Daily Express, Dublin, 1903 Feb 6 (Box 6, Folder 142e)
        C 7 and C 8
      - "The Soul of Ireland", review of Poets and Dreamers by Lady Gregory, printed version, Daily Express, Dublin, 1903 Mar 26 (Box 6, Folder 142)
        C 10
      - "The Motor Derby: Interview with the French Champion" [interview with Henri Fournier about Gordon Bennett Cup Race in Ireland], printed version, Irish Times, 1903 Apr 7 (Box 6, Folder 142g)
        C 11
      - Review of A Ne'er-Do-Well by Valentine Caryl [Valentina Hawtrey] printed version, Daily Express, Dublin, 1903 Sep 3 (Box 6, Folder 142h)
        C 12
      - "Aristotle on Education", review of review of Aristotle on Education edited by John Burnet, printed version, Daily Express, Dublin, 1903 Sep 3 (Box 6, Folder 142i)
        C 13
      - Review of The Adventures of Prince Aga Mirza by Aquila Kempster; review of The Mettle of the Pasture by James Lane Allen; and "A Peep into History", review of The Popish Plot by John Pollack, printed versions, Daily Express, Dublin, 1903 Sep 17 (Box 6, Folder 142j)
        C 14, C 15, and C 16
      - "Mr. Arnold Graves' New Work", review of Clytemnaestra: A Tragedy by Arnold F. Graves; "A French Religious Novel", review of The House of Sin by Marcelle Tintyre [i.e. Tinayre]; and "Unequal Verse", review of Ballads and Legends by Frederick Langbridge, printed versions, Daily Express, Dublin, 1903 Oct 1 (Box 6, Folder 142k)
        C 17, C 18, and C 19
      - "A Neglected Poet", review of George Crabbe by Alfred Ainger; and "Mr. Mason's Novel", review of The Courtship of Morrice Buckler, The Philanderers, and Miranda of the Balcony by A. E. W. Mason, printed versions, Daily Express, Dublin, 1903 Oct 15 (Box 6, Folder 142l)
        C 20 and C 21
      - "The Bruno Philosophy", review of Giordano Bruno by J. Lewis McIntyre, printed version, Daily Express, Dublin, 1903 Oct 30 (Box 6, Folder 142m)
        C 22
      - "Humanism", review of Humanism: Philosophical Essays by F.S.C. [i.e. F.C.S.] Schiller, printed version, Daily Express, Dublin, 1903 Nov 12 (Box 6, Folder 142n)
        C 23
      - "Shakespeare Explained!", review of Shakespeare Studied in Eight Plays by Hon. A. [Albert] S. [G.] Canning, printed version, Daily Express, Dublin, 1903 Nov 12 (Box 6, Folder 142o)
        C 24
      - Review of Borlase and Son by T. Baron Russell, printed version, Daily Express, Dublin, 1903 Nov 19 (Box 6, Folder 142p)
        C 25
    - THE RIGHT MAN IN THE WRONG PLACE (Box 6, Folder 143)
      - Manuscript 1 p., n.d.
      - E 11 b xxii
    - SHAW'S BATTLE WITH THE CENSOR
      See: LA BATTAGLIA FRA BERNARD SHAW E LA CENSURA, Box 3, folder 75
    - THE SISTERS
      See: DUBLINERS, Box 4, folder 86
    - STEPHEN HERO
      See: A PORTRAIT OF THE ARTIST AS A YOUNG MAN, Box 6, folder 138
    - TALES TOLD OF SHEM AND SHAUN
    - THERE'S A GEORGE OF THE GEORGES NAMED DAVID Manuscript 1 p., 1917
      - E 11 b xix
      - See: ALS from James Joyce to Claud W. Sykes, dated 1917 Sep 16 in Series I, Box 1, folder 24
    - THERE'S A HAIRY-FACED MOSLEM NAMED SIMON, 1917
    - TO BUDGEN, RAUGHTY TINKER Manuscript, n.d.; 2 (Box 6, Folder 144)
    - ULYSSES: Errata in the English Unlimited Edition. Typescript 1p., n.d. (Box 6, Folder 145)
    - ULYSSES, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 146)
      Page proofs: p. [1-8] 161-[176] E 5 g
    - WORK IN PROGRESS See: FINNEGANS WAKE
  - MUSICAL SETTINGS & ADAPTATIONS
    - OUT BY DONNYCARNEY, 1910
      F 1 Adolph Mann Chamber Music XXXI
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 38, folder 614.
    - 0 COOL IN THE VALLEY NOW, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 147)
      F 2 Louis Koemmenich Chamber Music XVI
    - GOLDENHAIR, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 148)
      F 3 Elliot Griffis Chamber Music V
    - FROM DEWY DREAMS, 1924